<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sigma Fitness</string>
    <string name="mountain"> Step 1:- Start in the push-up position with your arms completely straight and directly beneath your shoulders.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Your body should form a straight line from your shoulders to your ankles.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Squeeze your abs, lift one foot off the floor and bring your knee up towards your chest while keeping your body in as straight of a line as possible. \n\n
                             Step 4:- Return to the starting position and repeat the movement with your opposite leg ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY.. </string>
    <string name="pose2">    Step 1:- Lie flat on your mat with knees bent and feet on the mat. Hands at the base of your head and elbows pointed out. Using your abdominal bring your head and shoulders off the mat and come up into a crunch, then lower with control. ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY </string>
    <string name="tricep">   Step 1:- This movement is performed with a bench and a foot stool.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Place a bench behind yourself and rest on it with your hands. Place your legs straight out in front of you. You may also place them at an elevated level as shown above.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Begin with arms in a fully. Slowly bend at your elbows keeping the rest of your body straight. Be sure to keep your elbows back and close together.\n\n
                             Step 4:- Dip down until your arms form a 90 degree angle and you feel a stretch in the triceps.\n\n
                             Step 5:- Slowly extend your arms raising your body back up. Pause and contract your triceps muscles at the top. Pause and repeat the movement ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY.</string>
    <string name="abs">      Step 1:- Lie flat on the floor with your lower back pressed to the ground (pull your navel in to also target your deep abs).\n\n
                             Step 2:- Put your hands behind your head, then bring your knees in towards your Chest and lift your shoulder blades off the ground, but be sure not to pull on your neck.\n\n
                             Step 3:-Straighten your right leg out to about a 4S-degree angle to the ground while turning your upper body to the left, bringing your right elbow towards the left knee.\n\n
                             Step 4:- Make sure your rib cage is moving and adjust your elbows. Now switch sides and do the same motion on the other side to complete one rep ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY. </string>
    <string name="legraise"> Step 1:- Lay down with your hands to your sides for support. \n\n
                             Step 2:- Raise your legs so they are off the ground, keeping the abdominal tight.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Slowly raise your legs 90 degrees, contracting the abdominal muscles. Slowly return to starting position. Do not touch the floor with your feet. ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n
                            </string>


    <string name="alternate">    Step 1:- Lie on your back on an exercise mat. With your arms straight at your sides, bend your knees and place your feet flat on the floor between18 and 24 inches apart.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Breathing out, crunch your ab slightly upward and sideways to the right a couple of inches until your right hand touches your right heel.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Hold brief|y and then return to your starting position while inhaling. Repeat on the left side---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY. </string>
    <string name="legchrunch">    Step 1:- You can perform straight-leg crunches by lying face up on the floor with your legs straight and then moving your upper body as you would for a standard bent-knee crunch.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Alternatively, lie on your back, raise your legs so they are perpendicular to the floor and then perform the standard crunching motion with your torso.---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n
                             </string>
    <string name="lowerabs"> Step 1:- Lie down on the floor placing your feet either under something that Will not move or by having a partner hold them. Your legs should be bent at the kneesPlace your hands behind your head and lock them together by clapping your fingers. This is the starting position.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Elevate your upper body so that it creates an imaginary V-shape with your thighs. Breathe out when performing this part of the exercise.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Once you feel the contraction for a second, lower your upper body back down to the starting position while inhaling . \n\n
                             Step 4:- Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY .\n\n
                            </string>
    <string name="pose9">    Step 1:- Lying on the back,lift right leg,extend opposite hand to touch toe. \n\n
                             Step 2:- Please,return,alternate inhale down,exhale up at toe touch.---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n
                            </string>
    <string name="russian">    Step 1:- Make position then slowly rotate your torso to the side raising your arm till it gets in line with the other one. \n\n
                             Step 2:- Then return to the initial position ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY.\n\n
                            </string>
    <string name="chrunches">    Step 1:- Lie on the floor with elbows directly beneath your shoulders and legs fully extended.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Raise your torso into the air until it makes a straight line from your shoulders to your ankles. Tighten your stomach, squeeze your butt ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY.
                            </string>
    <string name="vup">    Step 1:- Lie down on the floor placing your feet either under something that will not move or by having a partner hold them. Your legs should be bent at the knees. Elevate your upper body so that it creates an imaginary V-shape with your thighs. \n\n
                             Step 2:- Your arms should be fully extended in front of you perpendicular to your torso and with the hands clasped. This is the starting position.\n\n
                             Step 3:- This is the starting position. Twist your torso to the right side until your arms are parallel with the floor while breathing out. \n\n
                             Step 4:- Hold the contraction for a second and move back to the starting position while breathing out. Now move to the opposite side performing the same techniques you applied to the right side. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n
                            </string>
    <string name="glutes">    Step 1:- Lie on your back with your knees bent, feet flat and hip width. \n\n
                             Step 2:- Lower your pelvis 2 inches from the floor. Squeeze your glutes and lift your pelvis back to bridge position. ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n

                            </string>
    <string name="extra">    Step 1:- Lie face down on the floor with your arms extended in front of you and your leg extended behind you. \n\n
                             Step 2:- In one movement,engage your glutes and lower back to raise your arms,legs,and chest off the floor.\n\n
                             Step 3:- Hold for a count,then slowly return to the starting position.---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n
                            </string>
    <string name="toetouch"> Step 1:- Stand, extend arms 90° to sides, bend forward 90° at waist.\n\n
                             Step 2:- Looking at the floor, rotate torso to touch hand to foot, rotate for other hand. \n\n
                             Step 3:- Head will follow chest action ---//ABHINAV CHOUDHARY \n\n. </string>

    <string-array name="title_array">

        <item>Muscle Building Tips </item>
        <item>Stay Hydrated </item>
        <item>Cold baths</item>
        <item>Static Stretching </item>
        <item>Meditation </item>
        <item> Fat loss tips </item>
        <item> Bulking tips </item>
        <item> Supplements and  their uses </item>
        <item> Sleep cycle </item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="detailed_story">

        <item><h2>Muscle Building Tips</h2> \n
            <h6>Focus on Protein</h6> \n
          Consume at least 1 gram of protein per pound of bodyweight on a daily basis. Protein provides the amino acids that are used as the building blocks of muscle protein. Although the recommended daily allowance for protein is set at less than half a gram per pound of bodyweight for the typical person, research shows that athletes, especially those concerned with muscle mass and strength, need roughly double that amount.
          Beginners should actually try to get in about 1.5 grams of protein per pound of bodyweight per day for the first six months of working out, since this is when your muscles will respond the most rapidly to training. For the 180-pounder, this means 270 grams per day at the outset and a bare minimum of 180 grams daily thereafter.
        <h6>Calories Count</h6> \n
        To build muscle, consume 20 calories per pound of bodyweight per day. You must stay in a positive calorie balance (taking in more calories than you burn) to gain quality mass. If you burn more calories than you consume (a negative balance), your body will go into conservation mode and won’t support new muscle growth.
        <h6>Eat Frequently </h6> \n
        Eat a meal that contains quality protein and carbs every 2-3 hours to ensure a steady supply of energy and amino acids for muscle growth all day long, helping you gain mass and stay lean. The key is to keep every meal approximately the same size.
        <h6> Eat Before Bedtime </h6> \n
       Before going to bed every night, consume 30-40 grams of a micellar casein protein shake or 1 cup of low-fat cottage cheese, as well as 2-3 tablespoons of flaxseed oil, 2 ounces of mixed nuts or 2-3 tablespoons of peanut butter. When you sleep, you essentially fast for 7-9 hours (or for however long you sleep).
        <h6> Carb Up </h6> \n
        Eat about 2-3 grams of carbohydrates per pound of bodyweight each day. Protein is the most critical macronutrient for muscle growth, with carbohydrates a close second. Carbs are stored in your muscles as glycogen and both keep your muscles full and large and fuel them during workouts. To gain mass, the 180-pound beginner will need 360-540 grams of carbs daily.
        </item>

        <item><h2>Stay Hydrated </h2> \n
            Conventional wisdom tells you 4-5 litres of water is enough per day.
            Since you are training for an unconventional physique, you need more. Aim for at least a half gallon to a gallon per day, depending your level of conditioning

         </item>
        <item><h2>Cold baths</h2> \n

            Taking an ice bath after you workout can reduce muscle inflammation, flush out lactic acid,
            and help your muscles to start the healing process after strength training.
            Research shows this is not better than a traditional cool-down, but it is a complementary way for your muscles to recover.


        </item>

        <item><h2>Static Stretching </h2> \n
            Static stretching requires you to move a muscle as far as it can go without feeling any pain, then hold that position for 20 to 45 seconds. You should repeat static stretches two to three times each. This is a very effective way to increase flexibility.

           Static stretches should be used as part of your cool-down routine to help prevent injury. Using static stretching as a maintenance stretching program will also help reduce your risk of injury.

          But using static stretching in a warm-up prior to an athletic competition may actually negatively impact your performance. This is because static stretching may limit your body’s ability to react quickly. This condition may last up to two hours in activities such as vertical jumps, short sprints, balance and reaction speeds.
        </item>

        <item> <h2>Meditation </h2> \n
          If you meditate on a regular basis, then you probably know how amazing it can feel. That sensation of deep centeredness combined with a quieter mind is pretty incredible, to say the least. And it’s no secret that meditation offers a slew of potential health benefits — such as lowered stress, depression, and anxiety levels. \n
          <h6>Exercising Your Mind To Achieve Your Goals</h6> \n
           Basically, meditation is like a workout for your mind. With time, repetition, and practice you get better at it. Additionally, meditation can help you refine your ability to visualize the results you want to achieve, while giving you the mental stamina you need to follow through. Powerful visualizations plus sustained, committed follow-through, can help you reach your goals like nothing else.
        </item>

        <item> <h2> Fat loss tips </h2>  \n
        <h6>Eat plenty of fruit and veg</h6> \n
         Fruit and veg are low in calories and fat, and high in fibre ,3 essential ingredients for successful weight loss. They also contain plenty of vitamins and minerals. \n
        <h6>Get more active</h6> \n
         Being active is key to losing weight and keeping it off. As well as providing lots of health benefits, exercise can help burn off the excess calories you cannot lose through diet alone.
         Find an activity you enjoy and are able to fit into your routine. \n
        <h6>Drink plenty of water</h6> \n
        People sometimes confuse thirst with hunger. You can end up consuming extra calories when a glass of water is really what you need. \n
        <h6>Read food labels</h6> \n
        Knowing how to read food labels can help you choose healthier options. Use the calorie information to work out how a particular food fits into your daily calorie allowance on the weight loss plan. \n
        <h6>Use a smaller plate</h6> \n
        Using smaller plates can help you eat smaller portions. By using smaller plates and bowls, you may be able to gradually get used to eating smaller portions without going hungry.
            It takes about 20 minutes for the stomach to tell the brain it is full, so eat slowly and stop eating before you feel full.
        </item>
        <item>         <h2> Bulking  tips </h2>  \n
        <h6>Eat More Calories</h6>  \n
        The key to success has been proven to be quite simple: if you want to build mass – either fat or muscle – you need to consume more calories than your body uses while resting. We recommend a calorie surplus of 300 to 500 calories per day \n
        Instead of going all out straight away, increase your calorie intake slowly. Otherwise, you may end up gaining more fat than muscle.\n
        If you are having a hard time consuming more calories, reach for nuts. Simply snack on a small portion of almonds, walnuts, or cashews in the morning or afternoon – as well as a source of valuable calories, they also contain a lot of healthy fats.\n
        <h6>Eat Sufficient Protein</h6> \n
        More calories? Check! However, it’s not just the quantity of food that matters – the quality does too. High-quality protein should account for 35 to 40 percent of your daily meals. Protein is the building material for your muscle cells. To build muscle mass, we recommend around 1.5–1.8 g of protein per kilogram of body weight . \n

           Whey Protein, fish, lean meat, tofu, seitan, eggs, cottage cheese or skyr, soybeans, chickpeas, and lentils are all good sources of protein. \n
        <h6>Take Breaks</h6> \n
        The last and most important tip for fast muscle building is to give yourself enough breaks – i.e. days with no training. If you have given your all in a workout, the muscles you have used will be pretty exhausted afterwards. To get ready for the next time, your body will repair the damaged muscle fibers and build substance during recovery, which means that the muscles
        grow. If you were to train again too soon, it could set you back significantly.
        Many studies point to the importance of breaks for muscle repair and growth.
        </item>

        <item> <h2> Supplements and  their uses </h2>  \n
        <h4>Whey Protien</h4> \n
         Whey protein is the protein from whey, the watery portion of milk that separates from the curds when making cheese.
        It is commonly used as a protein supplement.

         Whey protein might improve the nutrient content of the diet and also have effects on the immune system.

         People commonly use whey protein for improving athletic performance and increasing strength.  \n
        <h6>Dosage</h6> \n
        Whey protein is consumed, if your daily protien requirements are not meet.\n
        *use 1-2 scoops daily.\n

        <h4>Creatine</h4> \n

         Your body stores creatine as phosphocreatine primarily in your muscles,
        where it is used for energy. As a result, people take creatine orally to improve athletic performance and increase muscle mass \n
        <h6>Dosage</h6> \n
        use 3-5 gm of Monohydrate Creatine in water everyday , now you will have to take 4-5 litres of water to hold muscle mass \n

        <h4>Fish Oil</h4> \n
        The main reasons- *It helps to avoid any strechmarks on your body .* to make skin healty , to  make face brighter.\n
        The benefits of fish oil seem to come from its omega-3 fatty acid content.

        Fish that are especially rich in these oils include mackerel, herring, tuna, and salmon.
        The body does not produce many of its own omega-3 fatty acids. Omega-3 fatty acids reduce pain and swelling,
        and also prevent the blood from clotting easily. \n
        <h4>Multivitamins</h4> \n
        Multivitamins are a combination of different vitamins and minerals present in food sources.
        Consumption of multivitamins daily can help us to make up for nutritional gaps to boost our health naturally.
        Multivitamins are an instant way to fulfil our everyday demands of nutrition and to get our daily servings of all our vitamins and minerals.
        and at last they are used to fulfill any requirements to build muscles\n

        <h4>Ashwagandha</h4> \n
        Ashwagandha has antioxidant properties and helps in lowering oxidative stress and prevents cellular damage.
        It reduces the levels of cortisol and helps to keep your body in an anabolic state to enhance muscle growth.
        Ashwagandha is a stress buster and improves stamina and performance</item>

        <item> <h2> Sleep cycle </h2>  \n
      Sleeping for 7-9 hours per night is crucial, especially if you are looking to change body composition,
        increase muscle mass ,or if you want to be ready for your personal training session the next day.
        Sleep enhances muscle recovery through protein synthesis and human growth hormone release.</item>



    </string-array>

</resources>